Nyasha Green

(803) 310-3246 | NyashaGreenn@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/nyashathechampion/



Scan for a look into my work or go here: https://greennc.github.io/Master-Portfolio/

Professional Summary

Full Stack Developer graduate of the Midlands Technical College Tech Hire program. 4.5+ years of customer service, problem solving, organization, and leadership. Fluent in multiple programming languages and skills. Aiming to leverage my advanced technical skills and quick learning to build and create a better future.

Technical Skills

Web Programming: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Python, Django, SEO, Adobe Photoshop, Gimp, Bootstrap 3 &

4, PHP, jQuery, GitHub, WordPress

Software: Microsoft Office, SharePoint, WordPress, MySQL, AWS

Operating Systems: Windows, iOS, Android

Education

MIDLANDS TECHNICAL COLLEGE, Columbia, SC

December 2019

Full Stack Web Development Course

UNIVERSITY OF SOUTH CAROLINA, Columbia, SC

December 2014

B.A. African-American Studies

Relevant Professional Experience

WEB DEVELOPER, Columbia, SC

Freelance Web Designer

May 2019 - Present

- Collaborate with clients to generate web content to meet their needs
- Validate sites by testing JavaScript, CSS3, and HTML5 codes to ensure cross-platform compatibility
- Ensure all web site development follows W3C web standards and ADA compliance for accessibility and other good practices for web design and development.
- Utilize Bootstrap, Adobe Creative Cloud, Python, PHP and MySQL for web application UX design and functionality
- Apply SEO knowledge to web pages focused on local aspects.

U.S CENSUS BUREAU, Columbia, SC

Census Field Supervisor

Jul 2019 - Present

- Compile, record, and code results or data from interview or survey, using computer or specified form.
- Identify and report problems in obtaining valid data.
- Collect and analyze data, such as studying old records, tallying the number of outpatients entering each day or week, or participating in federal, state, or local population surveys as a Census Enumerator.
- Supervise or train others and maintain staff records.
- Teach field representatives the basics of data collection and accuracy in a classroom setting.

• Ensure accurate payroll information is completed in the system.

NATIONWIDE INSURANCE, Columbia, SC

Sales Manager/Training and Development Lead

Feb 2016 - Jan 2019

- Answered customers' questions about credit terms, products, prices and availability for Auto, Property, and Life Insurance.
- Supervised the company's workforce, which involved delegating tasks to staff members and scheduling.

 Analyzed data to determine which areas of the company needed improvement, provided input and trimmed excess costs.
- Automated previously manual billing process, accelerating customer payments and improving billing accuracy by more than 15%.
- Configure security settings or access permissions for groups or individuals.
- Identify the causes of networking problems, using diagnostic testing software and equipment.
- Troubleshoot network or connectivity problems for users or user groups.

VERIZON WIRELESS, Elgin, SC

Technical Support Team Lead

Feb 2015 - Feb 2016

- Supported 12 tech support specialists and inspectors who conducted 100+ trouble shoot and support action items per week.
- Answered user inquiries regarding computer software or hardware operation to resolve problems. (iOS, Android, Windows)
- Maintained records of daily data communication transactions, problems and remedial actions taken, or installation activities.
- Read technical manuals, confer with users, or conduct computer diagnostics to investigate and resolve problems or to provide technical assistance and support.
- Referred major hardware or software problems or defective products to vendors or technicians for service.
- Developed training materials and procedures, or train users in the proper use of hardware or software.